This holiday, discover your inner elf.
Elf is a comedy, family, fantasy film directed by Jon Favreau.
When young Buddy falls into Santa's gift sack on Christmas Eve, he's transported back
to the North Pole and raised as a toy-making elf by Santa's helpers.
But as he grows into adulthood, he can't shake the
nagging feeling that he doesn't belong.
Buddy vows to visit Manhattan and find his real dad, a workaholic.
Buddy, played by Will Ferrell.
Walter, played by James Caan.
Papa Elf, played by Bob Newhart.
Santa, played by Ed Asner.
Emily, played by Mary Steenburgen.
Jovie, played by Zooey Deschanel.
Elf is a 2003 American Christmas comedy film directed by
Jon Favreau and written by David Berenbaum.
It stars Will Ferrell as Buddy the Elf, a human raised by Santa's elves, who learns
about his origins and heads to New York City to meet his biological father.
James Caan, Zooey Deschanel, Mary Steenburgen, Ed Asner
and Bob Newhart appear in supporting roles.
Elf was released in the United States on November 7, 2003, by New Line Cinema.
It became a major critical and commercial success, grossing $228.9
million worldwide against a $33 million budget.
Ferrell's performance as Buddy, in particular, was praised by critics.
The film inspired the 2010 Broadway musical Elf: The Musical and NBC's 2014 stop
motion animated television special Elf: Buddy's Musical Christmas.
It has been hailed by many as a modern classic and is often listed
as one of the best Christmas films of all time.
The film explores themes of elves, dwarf, holiday, adoption, santa claus.
The tone is lighthearted.